<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Coral Playground | Dive Sites | RSS Feed</title>
        <link>http://localhost:3000</link>
        <description>Welcome to Coral Playground, your best source for dive site info in the Red Sea</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 17:09:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <image>
            <title>Coral Playground | Dive Sites | RSS Feed</title>
            <url>http://localhost:3000/coral-icon.png</url>
            <link>http://localhost:3000</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2023, Coral Playground</copyright>
        <category>Technology</category>
        <category>Scuba Diving</category>
        <category>Corals</category>
        <category>Marine Life</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abu Dabbab Dive Site near Marsa Alam, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/abu-dabbab</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/abu-dabbab</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 01:04:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Habili Ali is the largest Habili in the reef system known as St. Johns. Habili is the Arabic word for a reef that never rises to the sea surface, which means it is not yet an adult reef. The steep walls of the reef are covered in colorful soft corals and huge black coral sea fans. The average depth of the site is over 30m/98ft and in some places the wall drops down to 70m/230ft. Due to the exposed location of the reef, divers always experience some currents at this dive site.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abu Ghalawa Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/abu-ghalawa</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/abu-ghalawa</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 19:50:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[**Abu Galawa** is a diving area located north of Hurghada and offers six dive sites: **Abu Galawa, Shaab Abu Galawa, Sachwat Abu Galawa, Habibi Abu Galawa, Gota Abu Galawa, and Marsa Abu Galawa. Marsa Abu Galawa**, one of the dive sites, is suitable for divers of all levels due to its reef complex topography.



The dive begins at the mooring point situated at the entrance of a lagoon, which is about 5 meters deep and contains seagrass beds with sea horses. However, not much else is visible on the sandy bottom of the lagoon.


During the dive, divers can explore a coral block with stonefish sightings before reaching the drop-off. As they approach the drop-off, they will encounter beautiful table corals, and the underwater life becomes more abundant. The edge of the drop-off is at 16 meters deep, featuring small pinnacles of hard corals hanging down the slope. Moving further north, divers can spot an eel garden at approximately 14 meters deep.


Divers are advised not to miss the shallow part of the reef while returning to the boat. The reef wall can be followed at a shallower depth of 9 meters, providing opportunities to see bass, moray eels, scorpionfish, and small caves with glassfish.


The area is rich in diverse hard corals with stunning colors. The terrain slopes down to the drop-off, making careful exploration necessary to uncover its hidden treasures.


Marsa Abu Galawa hosts schools of colorful fish, including turtles, moray eels, and groupers, creating an enjoyable and visually appealing dive experience.


Divers can explore Marsa Abu Galawa in two ways. The first option involves diving south alongside a smaller reef, passing by an old lobster cage and a garden eel, crossing the plateau to reach the ridge, and returning to the boat. The second approach is to head straight ahead to the ridge of the plateau and then return toward the reef over the plateau, encountering a garden eel.


Overall, Marsa Abu Galawa offers a diverse and rewarding dive experience with its varied marine life, impressive coral formations, and unique topography.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abu Hashish Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/abu-hashish</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/abu-hashish</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 20:31:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Abu Hashish is the island at the center of a wide bay 90 minutes south of Hurghada. It is enclosed by a vast reef network, situated on a large flat and sandy plateau which leads to a steep drop-off. Due to its ideal location it was once used as drop-off point for smugglers bringing contraband into the country.A tongue of reef extends about 1km south of the island. The dive site is at its southernmost tip. There is a shelf between 15 meters and 22 meters outside, and beyond that a steep, but fairly bare, drop-off, usually with superb visibility. Inside the tongue of reef there are many table corals and ergs to be explored.The trip here can be choppy. Rough seas often make this site inaccessible from Hurghada although the site itself is well protected. Actually, it’s a desired spot for all levels of divers and custom made for all levels of training. Current is mainly north to south and strongest along the drop-off.
Your best bet is to leave the lagoon through an obvious channel filled with table corals, cross the shelf to the drop-off and follow it north. There are some beautiful caves in the 30 meter region. Return along the inside of the shelf and finish the dive back in the lagoon amongst the numerous ergs.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abu Nuhas Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/abu-nuhas</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/abu-nuhas</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 17:51:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Abu Nuhas dive site, located in the northern Red Sea, is renowned for its exceptional wreck diving opportunities. The site features at least 7 sunken wrecks, with four of them accessible for recreational scuba diving. What makes it even more attractive is that these wrecks are relatively shallow, making it suitable even for less experienced divers. Abu Nuhas is shaped like a large triangular reef, with an average depth of 24m and excellent water visibility ranging from 20 to 30 meters. It is home to a diverse array of marine life, with vibrant hard and soft coral formations adding to its beauty.\n\n While exploring these shipwrecks, divers are treated to an abundance of marine life, including schools of colorful fish thriving in the crystal-clear waters. The rich variety of hard corals further enhances the dive experience at Abu Nuhas. Known as "Shipwreck City," the site is a magnet for adventure-seeking divers interested in exploring history beneath the waves.\n\n The wrecks on the northern and rougher side of the reef at Abu Nuhas carry fascinating stories and include The Carnatic, a British passenger steamer from 1862, The Chrisoula K, a Greek cargo ship from 1981, The Giannis D, a Greek cargo ship from 1983, and The Kimon M, a Greek cargo ship from 1978.\n\n This dive site offers divers the opportunity to witness diverse marine life such as groupers, jacks, snappers, barracudas, and occasionally sharks and dolphins, adding to the thrill of the underwater exploration.\n\n Overall, Abu Nuhas is a well-known and exciting dive destination, where divers can dive into history, explore intriguing shipwrecks, and immerse themselves in the beauty and biodiversity of the northern Red Sea.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abu Ramada South Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/abu-ramada-south</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/abu-ramada-south</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[South Abu Ramada (also known as Abu Ramada South) is a dive site with huge reefs of hard and soft corals and sea fans sitting on a sandy bottom, and a very old wreck that is very much decayed. Aside from diving, the South Abu Ramada site is famous for being a good snorkeling spot. Photography lovers can also enjoy good conditions for taking photos.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Banana Reef Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/banana-reef</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/banana-reef</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 03:15:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[True to its name, Banana Reef in Hurghada is banana-shaped and sits at an average depth of 10 meters with visibility ranging from 10-30 meters. The oval reef is surrounded by shallow waters reaching 15 meters at its deepest point.

Banana Reef is ideal for drifting dives along the coral wall, so divers should bring a compass. Drifting allows you to fully explore the reef, rather than boats dropping you at one spot. Gliding along, you'll discover an anemone city teeming with clownfish, then reach the northwest pinnacle blanketed in vibrant soft corals. The northeast side contains caves burrowed into the reef, filled with marine life.

Across the reef, you can spot glassfish, eagle rays, turtles, angelfish, bannerfish, nudibranchs, and pufferfish. The bannerfish colonies are especially impressive. Emperor angelfish and other small reef fish thrive around the pinnacle and gorgonian coral formations.

The mild current makes Banana Reef suitable for divers of all levels. After about a 90-minute boat ride from Hurghada, you can experience spectacular drift dives along this unique reef. Just beyond the main section, an erg awaits, densely covered in soft corals and patrolled by predatory fish. Descending further to 20 meters reveals huge table corals and giant eagle rays gliding by.

While the southern reef is rather barren, the outer reef is ideal for drifting past coral gardens, anemone cities, caves, and pinnacles bursting with exotic marine life. With proper compass navigation, drifting is the best way to fully explore the wonder of Banana Reef.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Carless Reef Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/carless-reef</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/carless-reef</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This reef is about 15-18m/50-60ft deep and is located south of El Gouna, Egypt. It has drop-offs on all sides, the eastern one being dramatic and highly scenic. There are two huge pinnacles covered by corals on the plateau. Both pinnacles' tops are at 6-8m/20-26ft’ depth. There may be a current here. This mid-sea dive site is available in calm weather only.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deadalus Reef Dive Site near Marsa Alam, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/deadalus-reef</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/deadalus-reef</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Daedalus Reef is a 400-metre-long and 100-metre-wide offshore coral formation located approximately 90 kilometres east of Marsa Alam. Its remote location protected it from mass tourism, and today Daedalus is considered to be Egypt’s less-visited reef. The distance from the shore exposes Daedalus to strong currents, which promote an explosive growth of several hundred species of soft and hard corals, perfectly preserved thanks to the reef’s limited access. The dive site also has steep walls that drop down to vertiginous depths and an abundance of pelagic species, including various oceanic sharks such as hammerheads, longimanus, and threshers. Daedalus is suitable for experienced divers who are confident with currents and drift diving.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[El Fanadir Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/el-fanadir</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/el-fanadir</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Fanadir is one of the longest and straightest reefs in Hurghada. Located in the north, out of Hurghada’s bay it is a good diving place for a calm drift dive. The average depth 25m/82ft with the water visibility around 25-30m/80-100ft. Besides the main reef on the west side, the sandy plateau is slopping down from 12-22 m/39-72ft, where the drop off wall starts on the east, going down to 50m/164ft.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[El Fanous West Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/el-fanous-west</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/el-fanous-west</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Fanous means a kind of lighthouse in the Arabic language. They call this dive site Fanous because of the small light point located on the eastern part of the dive site. The reef itself is approximately 300 meters long and extends on the west side.

This dive site is about 30 minutes away from Hurghada by boat.

At El Fanous you can make 2 different dives: one on the east side and another on the west side.

Let’s talk here about the dives you will make on the west side: Fanous West.

When you start your dive, from the boat, of course, you will have the reef on your right side and follow it. The depth under the boat is about 7 meters. To continue the dive you will pass through a kind of canal before reaching a sandy lagoon.

You will cross the lagoon in the north-west direction keeping the reef on the right side. While crossing the lagoon you will see several small coral pinnacles where unexpected small inhabitants can be spotted.

When you reach the northern edge of the lagoon, you will continue north to an erg covered with hard corals that you can admire.

You will return to the boat on the other side of the lagoon, keeping another main reef on your left side.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[El Mina Wreck Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/el-mina-wreck</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/el-mina-wreck</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The El Mina wreck (Arabic for ”The Harbor") is a Russian-made T-43 minesweeper that was built between 1947 and 1957 for the duties of harbor protection and mine clearing. Later it was sold to the Egyptian navy, and in 1969 (the date is a matter of some debate), an Israeli fighter plane struck two large holes into her starboard side and she sank while anchored. Since then this 60m/197ft-long wreck has been lying on its port side in 33m/108ft of water at the stern, and divers can explore everything, including the blast hole on the starboard side, the propellers, and the rest of this wreck, which is in good condition. However, penetrating the wreck is not recommended, because the passages are small and tight. The sea bed around the wreck is littered with live ammunition, that divers are not allowed to touch. In 2 minutes divers will come across the Mohamed Hasabella, which is also worth visiting.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elphinstone Dive Site near Marsa Alam, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/elphinstone</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/elphinstone</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Elphinstone Reef or Sha'ab Abu Hamra is one of the most famous dive sites in the Red Sea. It is a reef around 300m/984ft in length, with average depth of 20-40m/60-120ft and average water visibility of 20-30m/60-100ft. Its spectacular walls drop far below 100m/328ft on both sides of the reef. Strong currents make this a perfect drift dive along the steep walls with many species of fish, corals, sponges, gorgonias and sea whips to observe.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Erg Sabina Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/erg-sabina</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/erg-sabina</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This is a small reef, although the luxury of rich marine life means that this dive site can offer an extraordinary dive. The erg itself is by nature best on the north face so concentrate on this side. Next to the reef there are a few big brain corals, around which schooling fish hover, facing the current. About 50m north there is a breathtaking little erg full of soft coral, glassfish and excellent camera angles. Take your time on the way out there and back, glancing underneath table corals and coral blocks and you will be in for a treat.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Erg Somaya Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/erg-somaya</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/erg-somaya</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Erg Somaya has an amazing coral garden with hard and soft corals and high beautifully overgrown coral towers. And a great drop off running far into the depth completes the picture.

The two caves that are located here, are also worth a visit.

When diving Erg Somaya in the south direction, you will find some nice pinnacles which are gorgeous because they are completely covered with the most colorful species of corals and teeming with anthias fish, glassfish and their predators casually hanging around and waiting for the best moment to attack.

At the north of the dive site, you will be able to explore one in the form of a pyramid and full of fan corals.

While diving Erg Somaya you really shouldn’t skip the caves between north and south, overgrown with soft corals and gorgonians.

Erg Somaya can dive as a drift dive. You will start the drift dive from the north of the anchorage and follow the eastern wall southwards to a superb coral tower where your boat will be waiting. This wall will appear to be a living wall full of cracks where small reef fish species may hide. After having admired the different aspects of Erg Somaya, go up along the main reef, where you will reach the boat.

Erg Somaya is considered to be one of the most stunning dive sites near Hurghada, with some colorful ergs, some nice caves and a spectacular drop off into the deep. So definitely worth diving at!]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Giannis D Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/giannis-d</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/giannis-d</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 17:45:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Giannis D was a general cargo ship built in Japan in 1969. The original name of the ship was the Shoyo Maru, and later the name was changed twice, because the vessel was sold twice. The second time the ship was sold to a Greek company that gave the ship its final name, the Giannis D. In 1983, this freighter collided with the reef and immediately sank with its cargo of timber. Now the wreck lies next to the reef with its stern on the seabed at a depth of about 24m/79ft and its mast at a depth of only 6m/20ft. Divers can penetrate the wreck and explore some of its areas from the inside.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gota Abu Ramada Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/gota-abu-ramada</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/gota-abu-ramada</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Gota Abu Ramada was also named the “Aquarium”, due to the variety of marine life. The depth of the dive site is around 100m/300ft with average water visibility 20-25m/65-80ft. There is an abundance of hard and soft corals and a great variety of marine life.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hamda Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/hamda</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/hamda</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hamda is located on the northeast side of the Big Giftun Island, at about 1 hour by boat from Hurghada.

Apparently, Hamda is situated below several rock formations straight over a white pebble beach.

Hamda is a small plateau dropping from 15 to 35 meters depth. On both sides, the plateau is bordered by a drop-off, which runs over in a steep wall easily reaching a depth of 50 meters.

Currents at Hamda are usually gentle and it is suitable for all levels of divers. But if you decide to make a drift dive at Hamda, you better be an experienced diver.

Hamda is also known as a cleaning station where small skids are waiting for the larger species to come for cleaning.

The dive starts at a big green and winding crater coral. Diving northwards, you will reach 2 large sandy areas, one at 15 meters depth and the other one at 18 meters depth. Little further the steeping wall begins and it is worth to take a look into the dark blue. On the way back you will ascend to the shallow area at the depth of 3 to 4 meters.

Remarkably Hamda is completely overgrown with beautiful colorful corals and it is definitely worth diving there because of the amazing color variations.

The underwater life at Hamda is above 15 meters, where you mainly spot many reef fish, sheltering in the different soft and hard coral species that are covering the wall.

On the plateau, you can encounter the usual moray eels, stonefish, scorpionfish, barracuda and sometimes even sharks and turtles. In the open water above the plateau, you will spot schools of Fusiliers, snappers, and triggerfish.

But also dare to look into the big blue, where you can spot triggerfish, jacks, barracudas, tuna, turtles and even, when lucky, reef sharks.

The appearance of whale sharks have also been reported, in the area of Hamda.

If you choose to make a drift dive at Hamda you will start from the north. The wall is more interesting along the way a few coral formations.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Panorama Reef Dive Site near Safaga, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/panorama-reef</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/panorama-reef</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[On the north side is a plateau at a depth of 25 meters with beautiful fan corals and beautiful table corals from Acropora. Keep an eye into the blue: kingfish, tuna, barracuda are often present. You can also meet the “caretaker” of Panorama, a very curious Napoleon. At 27 meters, a crack in the rock with giant fan corals and a school of glass fish has its hiding place here. Stingrays, blue-spotted stingrays, lionfish and moray eels live on the plateau. During your safety stop you can linger over Anemone City.

On the south plateau you are practically guaranteed to see several Napoleon wrasse. It is especially pleasant that there are many young fish. Pelagic species such as tuna visit from time to time, and other predators such as bigeye trevally and barracudas hunt in large schools of fusilier. Eagle rays, manta rays, white tip reef sharks, gray sharks, silky sharks, and even oceanic white tips have been spotted here.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ras Disha Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/ras-disha</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/ras-disha</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Ras Disha is also known by the name of Torfa Ras Disha or Disha Malagk. It’s situated 90 minutes from central Hurghada, Sheltered from the wind in a natural bay, it’s suitable for any level of diver and ideal for drift dives. Ras Disha stands for ‘fringing reef’.

Ras Disha is a shallow plateau with a sandy bottom. The bottom is profiled by pinnacles and an elliptical erg in the southern region of the site. Going northwest, this plateau takes on the shape of a narrow ledge, allowing access to a steep wall.

The beacon on the main reef serves as a landmark to start drifting along the wall to the north. You will be rewarded with a picturesque display of pinnacles on the plateau.

Your other bet is diving from the mooring network. You start by touring to the drop-off. Subsequently you do a lap describing a half circle hovering over the plateau. In the process you will pass the mentioned pinnacles. One pinnacle specifally, the one that lies closest to the main reef, is particularly photogenetic.

The wall is the place to be for butterflyfish and bannerfish, paired with surgeonfish and parrotfish. The local sandbed is infested with residential marine life. Hiding crustaceans and other invertebrates are hunted by frantically digging moses sole, blue spotted rays and torpedo rays. Gobies and shrimps are on the lookout from their burrows.

The pinnacles at Ras Disha are punctuated with cracks. Together with caverns bursting with glassfish they provide excellent photograpic momentums]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Salem Express Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/salem-express</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/salem-express</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 19:59:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Salem Express was a 100m/328ft long passenger and vehicle ferry that sank in 1991. Propellers, corridors, upper decks, the restaurant and the bridge can all still be seen. Passenger luggage such as rolls of carpet, stereos, bicycles and chairs can all be found in and near the wreck. Coral coverage and marine life is good enough here. The site is suitable for divers of all experience levels as the top of the wreck is located at only 10m/32ft of depth]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shaab Abu Nugar Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/shaab-abu-nugar</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/shaab-abu-nugar</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Shaab Abu Nugar near Hurghada represents rich marine life paired with several cleaning stations. The colorful corals are in pristine condition in many places.

This reef is one of the most northern dive sites of Hurghada, reaching almost the area of El Gouna at a 90 minutes sailing distance.  It’s a good choice for all levels of diving and training.

Sometimes the sailing can be rough in windy conditions, however, there are protected moorings on the site.

Some parts of this reef network are not attractive at all; whilst others offer superb shallow diving with an almost virginal quality to the reefs. If you can, dive the three ergs north of the tongue – they are magical.
The diving environments here are called Torfa Abu Nugar in the north with a delicate coral garden and the oval shaped Gota Abu Nugar reef to the east. In the south Erug Abu Nugar offers an exciting tour fom one pinnacle to the other.

Abu Nugar is a mid-sized reef with a fine choice of dive sites all around. The main reef emerges from a sandy bottom with dispersed coral gardens and pinnacles.

In the north, Torfa Abu Nugar stretches in east-west direction, featuring an exquisite garden. The large gardens of coral to the north ensure a very fine dive.

The elliptical reef at Gota Abu Nugar is situated to the east. The reef  touches the surface from a bottom covered in corals. Its size allows exploring to the full extent in one single dive.

Due south the Erg Abu Nugar features an impressive string of pinnacles, sitting on a sandy bottom, decorated with a lot of coral rocks.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shaab Eshta Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/shaab-eshta</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/shaab-eshta</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A narrow channel here separate two ergs. The smaller erg is to the west and the bigger one is to the east. This pinnacle is shaped like a a heart. Leading up to the top is a canyon-like passage.

Small clusters of coral blocks and table corals are dispersed over the sandy flats here and dominate the closer perimeter.

The bottom here is largely decorated with gentle swaying turtle grass. Head out into the turtle grass beds, where you’ll find a wide variety of unfamiliar fish.

At Shaab Eshta schools of barracuda often hover over just below the surface. They are waiting for food to swim by. The sandy bottom is the natural habitat for gobies in symbiosis with their shrimps.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shaab Maksur Dive Site near Marsa Alam, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/shaab-maksur</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/shaab-maksur</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Sha’ab Maksur, located approximately 28km/17mi off Hamata, is the easternmost reef in a group of reefs known as Fury Shoals. In Arabic Maksur means ‘broken’, which probably refers to the shape of the southern side of the reef. On its northern side, the reef starts at 22m/72ft and gently slopes to a plateau at 40m/131ft before dropping off to over 90m/295ft. The north side of the reef is the most exposed to the open sea and divers can only dive there when the sea is calm. The east and west sides of the reef are steep walls. The south side features a plateau at a depth of 18m/59ft and two large pinnacles that do not rise to the sea surface at only 6m/20ft. Due to the large size of the reef, divers may need to do up to three dives here in order to fully enjoy and explore this beautiful coral reef.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shaab Petra Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/shaab-petra</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/shaab-petra</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[There are mooring lines on the south side of each erg so you might start your dive on either one of them. They are both hill-shaped, and the hard corals in the shallows are in truly fantastic condition. The eastern erg has a huge brain coral at its end pointing in the direction of the coral garden making it look like a turtle resting on the bottom. At the other side there is a small cavern inhabited by a group of glassfish and a red tooth grouper chasing lionfish away to defend his supply of fresh food. The western erg is smooth-shaped and sits on a flat sandy bottom. A ‘figure of eight’ route here should take you about 45 minutes in a relaxed tempo.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shaab Sabina Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/shaab-sabina</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/shaab-sabina</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Shaab Sabina is consisting of the main reef, a protected sandy lagoon and an erg standing alone on the north.

North of the main reef, a maze of ridges and ergs makes the underwater landscape exciting and in the northwest is a delightful coral garden. The hills are densely covered with hard corals which are the shelter for small species of fish. It is like being in a valley surrounded by mountains of corals.

The corner of the top reef divides the northern coral garden from the sheltered southern side. The southern part of this reef is mostly dead. At about 150 meters of the main reef, is a picturesque shallow lagoon.

The nutrient-rich water has made the north side of the reef wall sparkle with life and the bottom around the erg is mainly sandy with some fire coral formations.

The most beautiful table and brain corals can be found at Shaab Sabina. Shaab Sabina is mainly dived for its impressive coral landscapes.

Dive into this exceptional coral garden, which drops in steps from the upper part of the reef to the bottom at 14 meters. A labyrinth of coral provides a wonderful view as the waves send downlight reflections dancing on the bright sandy bottom. In the south of this maze, the wall of the main reef stretches from a depth of 8 to 10 meters to the surface. The hard corals grow over each other and give the impression of a Japanese garden.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shabrur Um Gamar Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/shabrur-um-gamar</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/shabrur-um-gamar</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Shabrur Umm Gamar is located approximately 1km/0.6mi north of the island of Umm Gamar and is a submerged mountain blanketed in rich corals. The walls of the mountain are notable not only for their corals, but also because of the crevices and caves sheltering a variety of marine fauna species. In addition to the mountain, the site also has several wrecks of Egyptian boats, one of which can be reached at 20m/66ft deep. The two other wrecks lie at over 70m/230ft deep, and can only be reached by technical divers. The site is known for big fish and superb conditions for photography.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Siyul Kebira Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/siyul-kebira</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/siyul-kebira</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 21:20:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This reef dive site with depth 36m/118ft and water visibility averaging 30m/100ft, suits divers of all experience levels. The highlight of the dive is a small pinnacle at the turning point of the dive, it has lovely soft corals and is home to thousands of glass fish, small moray eels and a great variety of colorful reef fish. When there is a strong north current this dive can be done as a drift.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Giftun Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/small-giftun</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/small-giftun</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[At this site a drift is the natural choice even if the plateau also can be reached from the mooring. You drop next to a vertical wall and follow the current due south as it gives way to a shelf getting wider further south.
When the main reef curves to the west over the plateau the drop-off suddenly makes a few turns giving the edge a zigzag contour. 15m deeper (around 45m) there is a tunnel, which although spectacular, is out of reach for recreational divers.
All over the drop-off in this area huge gorgonias form a virtual jungle swaying in the current, whereas soft corals squeeze in wherever there is a space big enough to root. The plateau itself is a semi-covered coral garden leading up to the shallow parts of the wall, as well as the moorings.
]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turft El Shahed Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/turft-el-shahed</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/turft-el-shahed</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A shallow channel leads in a westerly direction from the mooring to the pinnacles that are the main attractions here. Northwest of the channel there is a mainly flat sandy bottom that is scattered with random coral blocks. If you continue to head north, you will reach a beautiful erg perforated by cavities and overhangs. Closer to the mooring, on the south side of the main reef the corals are not in such a good condition. A stonefish encounter makes the safety stop here worthwhile. Another option is to drift all the way to the neighbouring Banana Reef but this requires good air consumption and navigation skills.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Umm Gamar North Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/umm-gamar-north</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/umm-gamar-north</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
Umm Gamar is a long-isolated reef formed by an underwater mountain, near the island having the same name as the dive site and about 90 minutes away from Hurghada.

Umm Gamar means Mother of the Moon, a reference to the crescent-shaped wedge of the island at the top of the reef.
You can also dive on the north side of Umm Gamar but only when weather conditions are calm. Currents can be very strong at this place. This side of Umm Gamar is characterized by large table corals and a large school of fish. You can spot a lot of butterflyfish, blackfish and many other species. Here you can make very sheltered dives. If you are heading to the south part of Umm Gamar North you can see black corals and at a depth of 27 meters, you will find a cave in the reef. This side of the site is also known for encountering Spanish dancers even during the day.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Umm Gamar South Dive Site near Hurghada, Egypt]]></title>
            <link>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/umm-gamar-south</link>
            <guid>http://localhost:3000/dive_sites/umm-gamar-south</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 23:01:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Umm Gamar is a long-isolated reef formed by an underwater mountain, near the island having the same name as the dive site and about 90 minutes away from Hurghada.

Umm Gamar means Mother of the Moon, a reference to the crescent-shaped wedge of the island at the top of the reef.
At its south-eastern side, there is a very steep wall where many species of the pelagic hunt for smaller fish. There is also a small plateau at its western side which is full of small caves and overhangs. The site features a generally sloping wall which finally plummets into the deep.

Umm Gamar has a plateau on the south, at a depth of 14 to 24 meters with a beautiful coral garden where you regularly spot a turtle, batfish, moray eel and also Napoleon fish. On the way to the drop-off, you can encounter amazing coral towers, full of aquamarine life, such as glassfish and lionfish. These towers are above all covered with mesmerizing soft corals and fan corals. But don’t forget to take a look in the direction of the blue. You may see big pelagic fish passing by. You can also dive there starting from the coral garden and following the reef wall on the way back. You will see colorful fishes and sometimes turtles.]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>